in this lesson
we're going to talk about evaluating
logs using the change of base formula
so we know that log base 2 of 16
is equal to 4 because 2 to the fourth
power is 16.
but let's say if you don't know that
here's how you can use the change of
base formula to get the same answer
but here's the formula log
base a of b
is equal to log of b
divided by log of a
and the reason why it's called the
change of base formula is because
you can change the base
originally the base is a
but you can make it into any new base
we'll call it c
c could be 5 8 12.
as long as these two are the same it
doesn't really matter what c is
the equation will work
so log base 2 of 16
you can type it in your calculator as
log 16
divided by log 2.
now when you type it in your calculator
like this
it's automatically going to make it base
10.
so regardless of whatever the new base
is
you will still get the right answer so
go ahead and type that in log 16 divided
by log 2
and you'll see that is equal to 4.
try these two examples
use the change of base formula
to evaluate the two logs
so let's divide log 243
by
log 3.
the calculator will give you 5.
and it makes sense because 3 to the
fifth power is 243
next we have log of 343
divided by log 7.
and this
is equal to three
so that's how you can use the change of
base formula in order to evaluate
logs
you